<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Burrito Shack</title>
 <link href="http://burrito-shack.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://burrito-shack.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2019-05-05T10:14:43-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://burrito-shack.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Linsolv</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>One System to Rule Them All</title>
   <link href="http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/29/One-System-to-Rule-Them-All/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-29T00:57:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/29/One-System-to-Rule-Them-All</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning, I got an email about an &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubiquitousrat.net/?p=5013&quot;&gt;Article from Che Webster&lt;/a&gt; musing about an issue I’ve been wrestling with since I started running games: sticking with one thing. I’m one of the GMs who would start talking about the latest new game he’d heard about, or new idea he’d had, and that pretty much meant that the sign that the current campaign (never long-running) was over. And now I want to tell you how that all changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what? It’s got nothing to do with running a game I’m unhappy with. The same thing happened to me every few weeks, listening to RPG podcasts, even when I didn’t have anything going on. I passed the time at work listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://9littlebees.com/mudandbloodcast/&quot;&gt;Mud and Blood&lt;/a&gt; because they talked about Warhammer, and I was excited about Zweihander. I’m not excited about Zweihander any more, but I listened to a lot of material from them. I got excited about every single game they advertised and I wasn’t running a single thing. I canceled my play-by-post games. For about three months I had nothing going on. And then I started an experimental World War 2 game, hoping it would last me 4 to 10 weeks. That was in January and I’m still working on getting to the end of that one single mission. It’s, uh… gone a little off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, also in January, &lt;a href=&quot;/almighty-gold/intro/&quot;&gt;Almighty Gold&lt;/a&gt; was a twinkle in my eye. I had moved to 2nd shift, I was starting to get settled into my new job (by then 4 months old, so I suppose I was only barely settling in; I’m only barely settled in now!) and I was ready to get back to writing, if only a little. Well, I still haven’t, but that’s procrastination for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a project to work on. Something that was &lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt;. Something I could run games in, and something I could write fiction around. But if I’m going to write a setting, and then run it based on the idea that’s already in my head, I need a game that can be tailored to suit, rather than a system I can tailor a setting around. I can already hear people, barely past the title. “But GURPS isn’t the perfect system,” they might say. Or, perhaps more reasonably, “am I to infer that other systems are, according to you, worse than GURPS?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if there’s one thing that’s important to me, it’s being able to slow down. I don’t want to go on a honeymoon with a game. I want to be able to settle down, even if only for a few months, and really fall into the kind of lasting love that relationships are formed on. You can’t have a happy marriage when you’re chasing every skirt you see. You can’t have a happy gaming life when you’re chasing after the perfect game. The minute you stop searching for something better, and start trying to be happy with what you have, is the minute that you can actually start trying to appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not perfect. I love so many games. I like different ideas. Worse, I’m in several competing RPG scenes. People who love narrative games on one side, people who can’t stand them on the other. A group of players who all natively speak Russian; I know the word “пока.” The first time I talked to someone other than my faithful sounding board about Almighty Gold and got a positive response (“Why not just play the Battletech RPG” was a common response for a while) was like a revelation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve settled in with GURPS. There are rants I could go on. Things I &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; about GURPS. There’s a lot of material I don’t plan on ever using. I don’t think GURPS is sexy. I don’t get excited reading the Basic Set. I don’t really know anyone who does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don’t get the urge to tell my players that I quit and they’re welcome to join my next campaign with GURPS. Not even when I’m 4 months deep on what was supposed to be a mini-campaign that I never really cared about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if that’s good or bad, but I’m glad I have a relationship now, rather than a fling, and that’s not nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>GURPS Micro-Mecha v0.2</title>
   <link href="http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/27/GURPS-Micro-Mecha-0.2/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-27T22:20:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/27/GURPS-Micro-Mecha-0.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;patch-notes&quot;&gt;Patch Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few changes needed to be made to my previous design, from simple arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the damage was way out of whack. I had reasoned that a shot from a 20-foot-tall robot should essentially always knock out a normal person: 20 damage was a minimum on a hit. But that’s insane, when you scale it. The new damage values reflect the idea that the smallest round a mech of this size would be firing is equivalent, roughly, to a G36 rifle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I added a section on scaling armor to size. However, it’s a little clunky right now. I’m not sure whether I’m going to keep it this way, or try to refactor that rule into something more streamlined and scalable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve considered is adding frame types, particularly a light-and-fast type which has fewer hard points, and a heavy type, with more. But that does cause some difficulty in assigning table values, and eats up a lot of word count when the goal remains a one-page rule set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;micro-mecha&quot;&gt;Micro Mecha&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mecha-at-war&quot;&gt;Mecha At War&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default setting assumed here uses futuristic, laser-firing ‘Mechs of roughly 7 yards in height. For ‘Mechs at different levels of technology, increase Loaded Weight by 1 rank (with the matching decrease in Move) and decrease all other traits by 1 (do not double-tax Move) for every major technological leap backwards, or the opposite (decrease LWt and increase everything else) for the product of improved technology.
For ‘Mechs of lesser size, reduce all ranks including LWt by 1 per major size jump; of greater, increase all ranks including LWt by 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build a mech, you spend 18 Hard Points. Each of these represents a piece of equipment or mechanical feature of your mech. These fall into roughly five categories:
Armor, Movement, Power, Weapons and Support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;armor&quot;&gt;Armor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hard Point assigned to armor grants 4 dDR, and increases the Tonnage by 1 rank on the table (the default is 20 tons), along with a matching decrease in Move by 1 rank.
When a Mech takes damage, each die of dDamage, or 10 dice of regular damage, dealt at once reduces the overall armor by 1 dDR; Sundering weapons deal 2 dDR worth of damage per die. When scaling according to size, use the maximum Weapon Damage value for 1 hard point at default. &lt;em&gt;For example, if using a Size 4 ranks lower than default, armor grants 6 DR per power point, and is reduced by 1 per regular die of damage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;damage&quot;&gt;Damage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When taking damage that penetrates DR, roll a 6-sided die, multiply by a 6-sided die divided by 2 (1 to 3), and compare to the Hard Point list. The Mech makes an HT roll to avoid the system being disabled. If the system is already disabled, then it is destroyed on a failed HT roll. If the system is already destroyed, then roll HT to avoid the entire Mech being blown up. If more than 5 dDamage penetrates DR, continue rolling HT after a failure to see how badly the attack penetrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;movement&quot;&gt;Movement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hard Point assigned to additional legs ascends Move by 1 rank, with a default (for two legs) of 10. Regardless of the number of legs, movement costs 1 Power Point.
This requirement may be increased, with each Power Point further increasing Move by 1 rank per point. This must be decided when creating the Mech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;power&quot;&gt;Power&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hardpoint assigned to power generation grants 2 Power Points. These Power Points must be assigned during combat situations to allow movement, fire powerful weapons, and power support equipment.
Assigning and re-assigning Power Points occurs during the combat round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;weapons&quot;&gt;Weapons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hardpoint assigned to weapons can be grouped together into a single weapon or separated into multiple weapons, depending on preference, though this choice must be made at the time of generation (not in real-time).
Adding a Hardpoint ascends the damage scale by 1 rung, beginning with 1D. Up to 2 modifications can be added per Hard Point, which each add a 1-Power-Point requirement to fire (the default is 0). The modifications are chosen from the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heavy Damage&lt;/strong&gt; ascends 1 rank.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sundering&lt;/strong&gt; Deals extra damage when destroying armor; overall damage is reduced by 1 rank.1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armor Piercing&lt;/strong&gt; Divides dDR by two.1
Multi-Hardpoint weapons systems may take Heavy up to twice per Hard Point, each instance costing 1 Power Point as normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;handheld-weapons&quot;&gt;Handheld Weapons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-Handed Ranged deals Weapon Damage of 1 rank lower, and can take up to 1 Power Point upgrade if limited to 10 shots.
Two-Handed Ranged deals Weapon Damage, and can take up to 1 Power Point upgrade if limited to 10 shots.
Handheld Melee weapons deal Weapon Damage, and automatically choose between being Armor Piercing or Sundering. They then choose 1 further Power Point upgrade, which may be additional Sundering or Armor Piercing, or extra damage. Handheld Melee still cannot have both AP and Sundering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional equipment may be assigned to Hard Points, each of which is listed below, along with any Power Point requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weapons Jammer&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1 Power)&lt;/em&gt; Attacks made against the Mech are made with a –2 penalty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Targeting System&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1 Power)&lt;/em&gt; Attacks made by the Mech are made at +1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1 Power for all Arms)&lt;/em&gt; Either holds handheld weapons, or can be used for striking in melee (Weapon damage +1 Rank).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radar&lt;/strong&gt; Allows an IQ-based Electronics Operation (Sensors)/TL check to locate other nearby Mecha.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stealth Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt; Attempts to use Radar to detect the Mech are made with a –2 penalty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mecha-combat&quot;&gt;Mecha Combat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each turn, choose one action from those below, and move up to your Move in yards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Gunnery (Mecha)/TL&lt;/em&gt; check to deal  damage to one target per weapons battery. Each target past the first assesses a –1 penalty to all attacks that round.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evade&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Driving (Mecha)/TL&lt;/em&gt; check to give enemy Mechs –2 penalty to attack you for 1 turn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lock-On&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Electronics Operation (Sensors)/TL&lt;/em&gt; to grant a +2 to attacking a specified target on the next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power Allocation&lt;/strong&gt; Decide whether to act &lt;em&gt;quickly&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;carefully&lt;/em&gt;. Careful allocation takes the full turn. If done quickly, test Repair (Mecha)/TL. On failure, your Power pool shrinks by 1 until you reallocate. On a critical success, your Power pool expands by 1, until combat ends. On a critical failure, your Power pool shrinks by 1 until combat ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Rank&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;LWt&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Move&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Damage&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-14&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2/3”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-13&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;300 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-12&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;500 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;700 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,000 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-9&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,500 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 ft&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5 ft&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1/2D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 ft&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D-1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D+2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D+2 dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;300 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;500 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150 yd&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D cDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Almighty Gold PbP</title>
   <link href="http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/27/Almighty-Gold-Ultralite/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-27T20:49:49-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/27/Almighty-Gold-Ultralite</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things I took away from the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailanka.blogspot.com/2016/07/a-psi-wars-primer.html&quot;&gt;Psi-Wars articles&lt;/a&gt; by Mailanka, was the importance of actual play-testing in the course of iterating. And of course, I’ve done some iterating on Almighty Gold already. I’ve designed templates. I’ve tested all the various design methods on paper, except for my own. I really ought to get on that, because I did discover that 20 hard points might be way too many, or that weapons may be too powerful, when trying to toy with the idea of 1-foot-tall micro-machines (&lt;a href=&quot;/gurps/2019/04/23/GURPS-Micro-Mecha/&quot;&gt;Micro Mecha&lt;/a&gt; indeed!) with damage in mind (10 hard points put together onto a single huge gun, 4 into armor for DR - which doesn’t scale, and needs to! - and 6 points into legs) was dealing 1D dDamage. Though, to be fair, I did forget that I needed a power plant to move the legs! So I’d be reduced to 3 points of Armor (18 dDR, but it ought to be 30 DR) and with 1 PP to spare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, that’s not really my “ideal” setup. Probably I want, in version 0.2, to drop the damage rank to 5D at base. That way, for a 1-foot tall mini, I’d be looking at 7D, which is about the power of a large-caliber rifle. So I’ll be posting another new Micro-Mecha version tonight, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-players&quot;&gt;For Players&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main rules are &lt;a href=&quot;/almighty-gold/ultra-lite/&quot;&gt;GURPS Ultra-Lite&lt;/a&gt;, with the following specifics and additions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three points to spend.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allowed skills are as follows:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Armor-Knight &lt;em&gt;(Begins at Armor-Knight 1 for free)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Infantryman&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Celebrity&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Corporate Spy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advancement will be pointless. As time passes, you can spend time on training, and in-so-doing can advance in skills, including specializations (not discussed by Ultra-Lite). If you want to specialize, just let me know, and I’ll explain the entire thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When creating characters, the following information would be appreciated, in addition to your character themselves:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is the name of their immediate parent-company? What kind of industry does that company belong to? What kind of relationship does your character have with their sponsor?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is one problem in the city or town your character is immediately responsible for?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Choose one of the following, and give a short description (one or two sentences is sufficient):
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Your character is hunted by some person on a vendetta for past wrongs, real or imagined.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Your character has someone who depends on them who must be protected at all costs.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Your character has, or feels they have, a duty to a person or group other than their sponsor and the debt-slaves under their protection.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Your character has sworn a vow in front of witnesses (outside of their agreement with their sponsor). Breaking a publicly sworn vow, in your position, is a very serious crime. Your only connection to your sponsors, after all, is your word. If you can go back on your word in one vow, what’s to stop you breaking another?&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;During the game, each player has 3 Destiny Points to spend, which replenish at the end of every chapter. You cannot save up more than 3. These can be spent in the following ways:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turn a failure into success for 1 Destiny Point.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turn a critical failure into a failure, or success into a critical success, for 2 Destiny Point.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reduce the damage from any attack to 1 damage for Pilots, or 10 damage for Mecha. Counts as 2D for the purposes of armor reduction, for 1 Destiny Point.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>GURPS Micro-Mecha v0.1</title>
   <link href="http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/23/GURPS-Micro-Mecha/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-23T23:50:49-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://burrito-shack.github.io/gurps/2019/04/23/GURPS-Micro-Mecha</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s no reason not to admit that I don’t know what I’m doing, since it’s on a private blog! Even still, I don’t know what I’m doing. That’s important to establish off the bat. But let’s get on to the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gurps-mecha-is-a-mess&quot;&gt;GURPS Mecha Is A Mess&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not being very fair, am I? After all, David Pulver worked hard on &lt;em&gt;GURPS Mecha&lt;/em&gt;! Or did he work hard on &lt;em&gt;GURPS Spaceships&lt;/em&gt;? Or did he work hard on &lt;em&gt;GURPS Spaceships 4: Fighters, Carriers and Mecha&lt;/em&gt;? Or did Sean Punch work hard on the &lt;em&gt;Fourth Edition Basic Set&lt;/em&gt;, and I should build a Mech as a character on a 1000 point budget, giving his main cannons as Innate Attacks and scaling up handheld weapon damage somehow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the answer is “Yes,” and “All of the above.” Of course Pulver worked hard. Of course the &lt;em&gt;Basic Set&lt;/em&gt; is good. And there’s a good argument in favor of doing it both ways. But there are five separate systems for designing Mecha in GURPS, between 3rd and 4th editions. And all of them are complicated. Even &lt;em&gt;GURPS Spaceships&lt;/em&gt; is complicated, to a degree. It takes 28 pages to explain the systems on offer. &lt;em&gt;GURPS Spaceships 4&lt;/em&gt; has an explanation of Mecha which is drastically undercut, with only SM+4 designs and legs added, but the removal of Medium/Minor weapons for those designs, and no explanation of how to scale handheld weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in this mixture of 6 separate systems (Mecha as Allies, 3e &lt;em&gt;GURPS Mecha&lt;/em&gt;, 3e &lt;em&gt;GURPS Vehicles 2nd Edition&lt;/em&gt;, 4e &lt;em&gt;GURPS Spaceships 4&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pyramid #3/40&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;em&gt;Mecha Operations&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pyramid #3/51&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;em&gt;Modular Mecha&lt;/em&gt;), and with the hopes of running an Ultra-Lite Mecha game via Play-by-Post, I came up with a way to make things worse: I made another one, and I made my best effort to fit it onto a single page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;micro-mecha&quot;&gt;Micro Mecha&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mecha-at-war&quot;&gt;Mecha At War&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default setting assumed here uses futuristic, laser-firing ‘Mechs of roughly 7 yards in height. For ‘Mechs at different levels of technology, increase Loaded Weight by 1 rank (with the matching decrease in Move) and decrease all other traits by 1 (do not double-tax Move) for every major technological leap backwards, or the opposite (decrease LWt and increase everything else) for the product of improved technology.
For ‘Mechs of lesser size, reduce all ranks including LWt by 1 per major size jump; of greater, increase all ranks including LWt by 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build a mech, you spend 20 Hard Points. Each of these represents a piece of equipment or mechanical feature of your mech. These fall into roughly five categories:
Armor, Movement, Power, Weapons and Support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;armor&quot;&gt;Armor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hard Point assigned to armor grants 6 dDR, and increases the Tonnage by 1 rank on the table (the default is 20 tons), along with a matching decrease in Move by 1 rank.
When a Mech takes damage, each die of dDamage dealt reduces the overall armor by 1 dDR; Sundering weapons deal 2 dDR worth of damage per die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;damage&quot;&gt;Damage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When taking damage that penetrates DR, roll a 20-sided die and compare to the Hard Point list. The Mech makes an HT roll to avoid the system being disabled. If the system is already disabled, then it is destroyed on a failed HT roll. If the system is already destroyed, then roll HT to avoid the entire Mech being blown up. If more than 5 dDamage penetrates DR, continue rolling HT after a failure to see how badly the attack penetrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;movement&quot;&gt;Movement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hard Point assigned to additional legs ascends Move by 1 rank, with a default (for two legs) of 10. Regardless of the number of legs, movement costs 1 Power Point.
This requirement may be increased, with each Power Point further increasing Move by 1 rank per point. This must be decided when creating the Mech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;power&quot;&gt;Power&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hardpoint assigned to power generation grants 2 Power Points. These Power Points must be assigned during combat situations to allow movement, fire powerful weapons, and power support equipment.
Assigning and re-assigning Power Points occurs during the combat round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;weapons&quot;&gt;Weapons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Hardpoint assigned to weapons can be grouped together into a single weapon or separated into multiple weapons, depending on preference, though this choice must be made at the time of generation (not in real-time).
Adding a Hardpoint ascends the damage scale by 1 rung, beginning with 1D. Up to 2 modifications can be added per Hard Point, which each add a 1-Power-Point requirement to fire (the default is 0). The modifications are chosen from the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heavy Damage&lt;/strong&gt; ascends 1 rank.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sundering&lt;/strong&gt; Deals extra damage when destroying armor; overall damage is reduced by 1 rank.1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armor Piercing&lt;/strong&gt; Divides dDR by two.1
Multi-Hardpoint weapons systems may take Heavy up to twice per Hard Point, each instance costing 1 Power Point as normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;handheld-weapons&quot;&gt;Handheld Weapons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-Handed Ranged deals Weapon Damage of 1 rank lower, and can take up to 1 Power Point upgrade if limited to 10 shots.
Two-Handed Ranged deals Weapon Damage, and can take up to 1 Power Point upgrade if limited to 10 shots.
Handheld Melee weapons deal Weapon Damage, and automatically choose between being Armor Piercing or Sundering. They then choose 1 further Power Point upgrade, which may be additional Sundering or Armor Piercing, or extra damage. Handheld Melee still cannot have both AP and Sundering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional equipment may be assigned to Hard Points, each of which is listed below, along with any Power Point requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weapons Jammer&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1 Power)&lt;/em&gt; Attacks made against the Mech are made with a –2 penalty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Targeting System&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1 Power)&lt;/em&gt; Attacks made by the Mech are made at +1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1 Power for all Arms)&lt;/em&gt; Either holds handheld weapons, or can be used for striking in melee (Weapon damage +1 Rank).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radar&lt;/strong&gt; Allows an IQ-based Electronics Operation (Sensors)/TL check to locate other nearby Mecha.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stealth Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt; Attempts to use Radar to detect the Mech are made with a –2 penalty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mecha-combat&quot;&gt;Mecha Combat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each turn, choose one action from those below, and move up to your Move in yards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Gunnery (Mecha)/TL&lt;/em&gt; check to deal  damage to one target per weapons battery. Each target past the first assesses a –1 penalty to all attacks that round.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evade&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Driving (Mecha)/TL&lt;/em&gt; check to give enemy Mechs –2 penalty to attack you for 1 turn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lock-On&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Electronics Operation (Sensors)/TL&lt;/em&gt; to grant a +2 to attacking a specified target on the next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power Allocation&lt;/strong&gt; Decide whether to act &lt;em&gt;quickly&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;carefully&lt;/em&gt;. Careful allocation takes the full turn. If done quickly, test Repair (Mecha)/TL. On failure, your Power pool shrinks by 1 until you reallocate. On a critical success, your Power pool expands by 1, until combat ends. On a critical failure, your Power pool shrinks by 1 until combat ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Rank&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;LWt&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Move&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Damage&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-14&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2/3”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-13&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-12&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;300 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;500 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;700 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-9&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,000 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D-2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8”&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D-1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 ft&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5 ft&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D+2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 ft&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D+2 dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7D dDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;300 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D cDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;500 ton&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1D+2 cDMG&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
